Samyak Jain

26 Bowman Street • Macquaire, ACT • (+61) 415-412-545 • samyak1901@gmail.com

Portfolio :https://u6734495-samyak.github.io/Samyak Jain Portfolio 2/

Github : https://github.com/u6734495-Samvak

LinkedIn : https://www.linkedin.com/in/samyak-jain-a20623107/

OBJECTIVE

Computer Science has been exciting and allowed me to learn new things every day of my life. It is thrilling to gain insights and work on real-life projects for clients within a team environment. Bachelor's graduate in Intelligent Systems with a strong interest in Machine Learning and Artificial Intelligence. Proven track record of working alongside senior team members to provide customer and consumer analytics and data solutions to a blue-chip client base. Experience in contributing to the development of core company data and services.

EDUCATION

Australian National University, Bachelor of Advanced Computing (Hons)

2018-2021

Courses Completed: • Foundations of Computing • Data Wrangling • Data Mining • Information Theory • Strategic Thinking: Game theory • Intro to Machine Learning • Document Analysis • Advance Computing Research Methods • Software Design Methodologies • Intro To Data and Security • Advanced Computing Project • Neural Networks: Deep Learning • Statistical Machine Learning • Computer Vision

2016-2018

International Centre for Applied Sciences – Manipal University, Bachelor of Science

Research Thesis: Computational Alloy Design and Discovery (Magnesium)

Employed various machine learning models to build a predictive modeling approach to better inform industry experts about using Magnesium alloys with ideal mechanical properties to make lightweight vehicles. Focus was to use machine learning to predict alloy compositions that could be useful for future metallic alloys.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Data and Solutions Analyst, SMRTR - Jan2021 - Present

1. Responsible for handling and interpreting large quantities of data from multiple sources and dealing with any queries.

- 2. Develop and facilitate the ingestion, transformation, extraction, and loading/delivery of data to clients and partners compliant with internal security processes and Australian privacy regulations.
- 3. Conduct analysis using a variety of methods including machine learning on client customer data to address client needs.
- 4. Assist in productization of analysis to improve efficiency and understand the big picture of how different solutions fit together.
- 5. Develop visualizations for clients to creatively communicate analytics outputs effectively with stakeholders and articulate technical issues to non-technical users.
- 6. Working with tools like Spark, Databricks, LLM models and API's to streamline processes and create efficient and effective chatbots

App- Developer, Australian National University - July 2018-November 2018

Built a small and simple game called Frogger which is an adaptation of the PC version of the game. Team project and included heavy involvement in developing the User Interface and back end code.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Proficient – Python, C++, OpenCV, Tableau, TensorFlow, SQL, Databricks, Spark, Keras, PyTorch

Familiar – JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Data structures, Statistical Modelling.

SOFT SKILLS

Communication skills – Interacting with people from various cultures.

Teamwork – Working cohesively in a team environment for the Frogger Game.

Independent Working skills – Ability to work with minimum supervision during research thesis.

Research Papers at ANU:

Network Reduction Technique For Classifying Faces Emotion.

Transfer Learning (Neuron Distinctiveness)